{
    "id": "c1ad9f79d0d94ab69b1ce1b1c276da28",
    "title": "Simple Past vs. Present Perfect vs. Simple Present vs. Past Perfect",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "744bea982f7a41639aef6510729c0022",
            "title": "Simple Past vs. Simple Present vs. Present Perfect vs. Past Perfect",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I ................................ for hours but he didn’t come.",
                    "description": "The simple past is the most normal tense for talking about finished events. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "waited",
                        "wait",
                        "have waited"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She ..................................... in several movies.",
                    "description": "We often use the present perfect to give news. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "acted",
                        "has acted",
                        "acts"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The train ………………………….. a few minutes ago.",
                    "description": "The simple past is the most normal tense for talking about finished events. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "left",
                        "has left",
                        "leaves"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Make sure that you ………………………… on time.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "arrive",
                        "have arrived",
                        "arrived"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The poor man made sure that his children never ………………………..",
                    "description": "When the main verb is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too will be in the past tense.",
                    "answers": [
                        "starve",
                        "starved",
                        "have starved"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You will get the promotion if you ………………………….. it.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "deserve",
                        "deserved",
                        "have deserved",
                        ""
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "They realized that they ………………………… a major blunder.",
                    "description": "The past perfect is used for the earlier of the two past actions. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "committed",
                        "have committed",
                        "had committed"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "We ……………………………. anything from them in over a month.",
                    "description": "The present perfect is used to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "did not hear",
                        "have not heard",
                        "had not heard"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "They …………………………. two wickets before rain interrupted the match.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "took",
                        "have taken",
                        "had taken"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Dad ………………………….. home from work at",
                    "description": "The simple present is used to talk about habits and routines. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "reaches",
                        "has reached",
                        "had reached"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Mother ………………………………. the weekends with her parents.",
                    "description": "The simple present is used to talk about facts and routines. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "spend",
                        "spends",
                        "has spent"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She started crying as soon as she ………………………… me.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "saw",
                        "has seen",
                        "had seen"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}